１５年ほど前から 世界大会が行われていますが
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
東ゴルトー代表は いまだ無敗です。
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
現世界王者は３代目で 大会５連覇中。
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
そいつに勝てば 余が世界一ということか。
The word "unknown" holds magic.
余戯の締めくくりに　ふさわしい。 呼べ。
And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
ネフェルピトーが進める 選別まで　残り６日
We entered the long and difficult path.
それまでの時間を 宮殿内で過ごす王は
Then cut a hole in the wall, to sneak into the short and easy path.
将棋や囲碁の名人を次々に下し 最後に残った軍儀の世界王者を
In an extreme situation, you were able to calmly evaluate
今　そば近くに招き入れた
our two options and circumvent them. That's what makes you special.
え…　え
The twenty-four applicants who have passed the exam's Third Phase
こ…　この度は おまぬぬ…　おまきね…。 前置きなどよい。 お前と軍儀で勝負をする。
exit Trick Tower, one by one, for a long-awaited breath of fresh air.
ワダす　ホントに バカなもので 世の中のこととか 何にも知らねえっす。
Ladies and gentlemen, congratulations
on having escaped Trick Tower.
口の利き方とかも　全く…。
Only the Fourth Phase and
the Final Phase remain.
気が散る　黙れ。
Two more...
殺すぞ。
The Fourth Phase will take place
over there, on Zevil Island.
よし　大体　分かった。 やるぞ…　ん？
Lots? For what?
どうした？ 失神してますね。
To determine who will hunt
and who will be hunted. In here are twenty-four numbered cards.
「黙れ」と言われ　口を閉じて 鼻が詰まっていたため
In other words, your ID numbers
are on the cards.
呼吸ができなかったと 推察されます。 ふむ…　まれに見る阿呆だ。
Now, I need you each to draw a card, in the order by which you
exited the tower. Will the first person come forward?
お前　目が見えるのか？
Guess I'm next.
いいえ　全く。 なので 読み駒をお願いいたすます。
I'm next.
お気に召さないようですたら 閉ずますが。
Hey, Killua. Huh?
別に　構わぬ。
He said something about hunting
and being hunted.
明らかに空気が変わった
Yeah, probably.
チッ　あっちからの連絡を 待つしかねえのかよ。 何だ？　あの時代錯誤 まるで隠さねえスタイルはよ
I don't know what this is all about, but I draw with style...
あの上目遣いが 自身の深い猜疑心あらわだぜ こいつとは 合う　合わねえ以前
Everyone's taken a card? Then, remove the seal from your card.
ゴン　残念だが こいつらの初見は超バッド！ よほどナイスなニュースが この先　ない限り
The card indicates your target.
クゥン…。 ねぇ　どうしたの？
This box has recorded which card
さぁな　野犬の群れだろ。
each of you drew.
首輪してるんだけど。
This means that you're free
選別のせいで 置き去りにされていた動物
to dispose of the cards if you wish.
全部に餌　やってたんだ。
The objective
寝る時間まで削ってな。
is to steal your target's ID tag.
全部じゃねえよ！ 時間がねえのは分かってる！
Oh, so we don't need to kill each other.
んなことしてる場合じゃねえ ってのもな！
Naturally, you're free to use
any method you choose
だから　明らかに ダメそうなやつは見捨てた！
to steal the ID tags.
偉ぇだろうが！
Including killing your target and
taking the tag off the corpse.
ガリッガリなのに　俺が餌 やっても決して食べねえやつ！
That sounds like the fastest way.
鎖　外しても 家から動こうとしねえ。
S-So that's what this is about?
バカみたいに利口なやつもいた。
Fool, there's nothing to be scared of.
そんな中で 救いを求めて来るやつくらい
Listen carefully!
助けて何が悪い！
Your target's ID tag is worth three points.
何も　泣くことないだろう。
Your own ID is also worth three points.
な…　泣いてねえよ　バカ！ てめぇ　しばくぞコラ！
All other ID tags are worth one point. You need six points to advance
to the Final Phase.
フン　そんなことじゃ 好感度　上がんねえぜ まぁ　少しはアレだけど
So while on Zevil Island, you must gather enough ID tags
to total six points.
７－８－２　「忍」　詰みです。
I will serve as your guide. My name is Khara!
地駒に弓を据え 攻防の拠点とする戦略
It will take two hours for
this boat to reach Zevil Island.
古典的な高矢倉だ
All twenty-four applicants remaining here
指し筋にも 何ら変わったところはない
are automatically qualified
to take next year's exam!
初期陣形も入門書レベル
So if you fail this year, don't feel bad.
余のほうが　まだ本気で戦うに 値せぬということか
Please try again next year...
もう１局だ。
Th-This is so depressing.
はい！　喜んで！
The battle has already begun.
８－８－１　「騎馬」。
Yeah, everyone's removed their ID tags, and hid them.
詰みだな。
Well, you're free to do as you like, for the next two hours.
いや　総帥様ってば 恐ろすく　覚えが早いっす！
Please enjoy the boat ride.
足元　すくわれかねねえっす！ もうよい　下がって休め。
Speaking hypothetically...
はっ…　いえいえ ワダすなら全然　平気っす！
If you happened to be my target, I wouldn't show any mercy.
軍儀ならば 三日三晩　寝なくとも…。
Naturally.
先客がおる。
If you happened to be my target,
I would say the same.
そいつを片付けたら　お前の番だ。
Am I your target?
へば　少すだけ 休ませていただきます。
I was speaking hypothetically. Oh, right...
時間の問題だな。 選択肢は多いが
Yo.
さすれば 奴の呼吸も見えて来る。
What number did you draw?
何ら変わらぬわ。
How about you?
ハハハ…！
You aren't my target.
あの阿呆を呼び戻せ。
And my target isn't you.
王が宮殿内で
#44 is...
軍儀名人の少女との戦いを 繰り返していた頃 そこから離れた 首都　ペイジンでは
Seriously?
モラウが自らの能力を使い
You have really bad luck...
街全体の包囲を進めていた
You think so? Who's #199?
むん！
After the initial explanation, I started checking tags, but everyone had already removed them.
まず　核となるオーラを発し…
That's so lame...
それを　煙のオーラで覆うと 核のオーラに込められた
Gon... Huh?
「念」の操作条件に従って 自在に動き回る
What? Are you happy?
煙人形が完成
Or scared?
やや操作情報を 複雑にしてるから ５０体ぐらいしか 同時には出しておけないが
In a straight-up fight, I wouldn't stand a chance.
その分　高性能 「円」では　人か人形か 区別しきれないのも
But if I only need to steal his ID tag, then I have a real shot.
こっちの　大きなアドバンテージ
Yeah. Right now, I might actually have a chance.
かといって ネフェルピトーは　アリの性質上
That scares me a little...
王のそばを離れない
But I think it's worth it.
案の定　すぐに操り人形を 首都に集結させ
I see.
防御重視の構え このことからも　奴ら護衛団の 優先順位のトップが
Well, let's do our best.
王の安全だと分かる
Make sure you stay alive, Gon.
奴らの動きを縛るのは　超簡単
Uh-huh! You, too.
勝手気ままに動くような 奴だと　次を読みにくいし
Thanks for your patience, everyone. We've finally arrived at Zevil Island!
突発事故が怖えぇ
Now, please disembark in the order by which
ん？
After each person disembarks, we'll wait two minutes before
the next person's turn.
久しぶり。
That means we'll be waiting
here a while.
会いたかったぜ。
Yeah.
チッ　レベルが上がってるな
You will stay on this island
for exactly one week.
前とは雰囲気が違う
During that time, you must amass your six points
of ID tags and return here.
ナックルの ポットクリンがついてねえ トリタテンに 変わった気配もねえし
All right then, the first person may start!
ポットクリンが 消えてるってことは
I understand...
「念」を外せる奴がいる？
Those who disembark earlier
hold the advantage.
それとも　奴自身が除念を？
Yeah. They can hide and monitor
お手並み拝見だ
their target's movements. Two minutes have passed.
どっちが勝とうが 最後に得をするのは
The second person may start!
借りを返すよ。
The third person may start.
まずは　あんたを　かたにはめて
Yeah! The seventh person...
次は　リーゼントだ！
The eleventh person...
何か新しい能力を得たな
The twentieth person may start.
それが　もし 除念の能力だとしたら　マズい
The twenty-first person may start! See ya. Uh-huh.
完全なヒット　アンド　アウェー ナックルの「ハコワレ」を シュートがサポートする作戦だ
Well, guess I'll begin by scouting the island.
しかし　こちらの「念」で 相手の「念」を封じ込める作戦は
Two minutes have passed. The twenty-second person may start.
敵の中に除念師がいれば 全く無意味になる
Okay! See you... Yeah!
王にさえ通用するかもしれない 戦法が無意味に
First, I need to find Hisoka!
だが　もし こいつの能力が除念ならば 今は逆にビッグチャンス ここで　こいつを仕留めておけば ナックル達が生きる
Hunter Vocabulary Zevil Island
「ディープパープル」は 解除するわけにはいかない 残りのオーラで何とかする
How do I steal Hisoka's ID tag?
うおっ！
Such a good boy.
何だ？　相変わらず スピード頼りの単純攻撃かよ なら　いくらでも 対処できるぜ　足だけ野郎
Very nice. I'm getting excited now...
ん？
I won't be able to steal his tag
with a head-on attack...
な…　何だ？　ここは サバンナ？
It's another applicant.
どこかに 飛ばされたってことか これが奴の能力なら 除念は別のアリの能力
And another one is behind him.
最悪 ボっとしてていいの？
He's targeting the guy in front.
フゥ。
He blew it!
あっ。 ヘイ！ 俺の話を聞いてたかい？
Hey, that was close.
俺にタッチしなきゃ ここは出られないんだぜ！
Sorry, but it won't be that easy...
だからって　遮二無二 追っかけたって捕まらんだろ？
That easy... Wh-What?
まぁ　じっくりとやるさ。
B-Bastard...
うん…。
The arrow was coated with
a fast acting tranquilizer.
どんな能力かは知らんが
See ya.
これで８時間は戻って来ない
Wow.
背景は壁
as he stalked his prey.
奴の言う通り 現実世界から隔絶された 念空間のようだな
And his target was able to
sense the shot being fired, and quickly dodge it, avoiding serious injury.
広さは 野球のグラウンドほどか 「ディープパープル」を 解除　回収すれば
However, the other applicant anticipated this, and poisoned his arrow...
この空間を 覆い尽くす煙は余裕で出せる
This is how you hunt!
隔絶空間から果たして 解除の操作ができるのか ２つ 解除操作が　できたとしても そのオーラを　この空間に 戻すことができるのか？
If I have any chance at
stealing Hisoka's ID tag, this is it!
そのオーラを　この空間に戻せず 回収できない場合
First, I have to sneak up on him without being noticed.
一度　解除してしまったら オーラを回収してからでないと 発動し直すことが　できない
Then I wait for my chance, and steal his tag!
試すには　リスクが高過ぎる
Yeah!
おっ！ 「ディープパープル」の 解除はできない 少なくとも　今はまだ
But unlike this target,
Hisoka will be moving...
ようやく　やる気になったかい？
Regardless, I'll only get one shot.
鬼さん　こちら 手の鳴るほうへ
I have to hook Hisoka's tag when he isn't paying attention.
おっ？
Okay...
その…　まさかだよ！
Read his movements...
この俺を 捕まえることだけだってば。
Hmm...
こいつの能力
This isn't quite right...
明らかにナックルの 「ハコワレ」の影響を受けてるな
It's too easy to predict
てことは…
how a swinging target will move.
さぁねぇ そこまで教える義理はないな。
That's right.
そりゃそうだ。
I shouldn't forget that Hisoka will
try to move out of the way.
５時間たったら起こしてくれ。 うぅ…　ナメてんのか？
If I can't get a bird by watching how it moves, I'll never be able to steal Hisoka's ID!
お前　根本から 自分の能力を誤解してるよ
Huh?
これは脚力の戦いじゃ　ねえ 心の削り合いだよ
Oh, well! I won't catch a bird on the
first or second try.
作戦続行ということだな
Whose number is this?
テレパシー もう１人　主犯格らしき人物を 発見しました。
The sun's about to set...
テレパシー 黒スーツで眼鏡をかけた 黒髪の男です。
I should probably stay in one place
until tomorrow morning.
テレパシー いえ　あとは同じ 白装束の連中だけです。
Damn...
周りの連中は　多分 ただの兵隊だろうが
I didn't think it would be so hard.
もしかしたら　本当のリーダーが
It's too dark for me to see anything.
そこに紛れている可能性もある
And all the birds are gone...
それに　誰であれ　俺の能力を 見られるのは避けてぇし
Okay... I'll catch one tomorrow!
オッケー　その代わり 確実にそいつを仕留めてね
Right! Back to training!
何が起きるか分からないし
It's no use.
できれば王には 選別が完全に済むまで
Maybe it's not possible, after all.
この中にいてもらいたいから。 ご用ですね？
To catch a bird, with accuracy, while it's in flight...
どう？ 少し雲行きが怪しくなってきた。 ニャ？
Birds can catch fish that are swimming.
妙なツケの連打で 一気に形勢が変わった
I get it... There's a moment
４－５－１　「筒」。
when I know exactly what
my target will do next!
完全に右辺が殺された
Now!
ない　詰みだ。
I did it!
バカな…　置き駒から 詰みまでの１４４手
I figured it out! I have to aim for my target as
he hunts his own prey!
余の打ち筋を全て読まねば この手には至らぬ
Heh.
次だ。
He actually mastered
the art of hunting.
はい！
Impressive little boy...
絶対にあり得ぬ
But that intense concentration
will be your undoing.
荒れるね。 少女の強さに　いら立つ　王
Gon finally mastered the trick that
would help him hunt Hisoka.
宮殿に嵐が近づいている
However, Gon was also being hunted.